compareandrecycle.co.uk 2017-06-06

# Privacy Policy - Compare and Recycle

### Commitment to your privacy

This site is owned and operated by Compare and Recycle. Your privacy on the Internet is of the utmost importance to us. At Compare and Recycle, we want to make your experience online satisfying and safe. 

Because we gather certain types of information about our users, we feel you should fully understand our policy and the terms and conditions surrounding the capture and use of that information. This privacy statement discloses what information we gather and how we use it. 

### Information Compare and Recycle gathers and tracks

Compare and Recycle gathers two types of information about users: 

  * Information that users provide through optional, voluntary submissions. These are voluntary submissions to receive our electronic newsletters, to participate in our message boards or forums, to email a friend, and from participation in polls and surveys. 

  * Information Compare and Recycle gathers through aggregated tracking information derived mainly by tallying page views throughout our sites. This information allows us to better tailor our content to readers' needs and to help our advertisers and sponsors better understand the demographics of our audience. Because Compare and Recycle derives its revenue mainly from sponsorships and advertising, providing such aggregated demographic data is essential to keeping our service free to users. Under no circumstances does Compare and Recycle divulge any information about an individual user to a third party. 

Compare and Recycle gathers user information in the following processes: 

### Optional voluntary information

We may offer the following free services, which require some type of voluntary submission of personal information by users: 

  1. Electronic newsletters policy (Dispatches) 

We will offer a free electronic newsletter to users. Compare and Recycle gathers the email addresses of users who voluntarily subscribe. Users may remove themselves from this mailing list by following the link provided in every newsletter that points users to the subscription management page. Users can also subscribe to the newsletters at the time of registration. 

  2. Message boards/forums policy 

Users of the site's Message Boards and Forums must register for these services (both are free of charge) in order to post messages, although they needn't register to visit the site. During registration the user is required to supply a username, password, and email address. 

  3. "E-mail this to a friend" policy 

Our site users can choose to electronically forward a link, page, or documents to someone else by clicking "e-mail this to a friend". The user must provide their email address, as well as that of the recipient. This information is used only in the case of transmission errors and, of course, to let the recipient know who sent the email. The information is not used for any other purpose. 

  4. Polling 

We may offer interactive polls to users so they can easily share their opinions with other users and see what our audience thinks about important issues. Opinions or other responses to polls are aggregated and are not identifiable to any particular user. Compare and Recycle may use a system to "tag" users after they have voted, so they can vote only once on a particular question. This tag is not correlated with information about individual users. 

#### Children

Consistent with the Federal Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA), we will never knowingly request personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13 without requesting parental consent. 

#### Usage tracking

Compare and Recycle tracks user traffic patterns throughout this site. However, we do not correlate this information with data about individual users. Compare and Recycle does break down overall usage statistics according to a user's IP address and browser type by reading this information from the browser string (information contained in every user's browser). 

Compare and Recycle sometimes tracks and catalogs the search terms that users enter in our Search function, but this tracking is never associated with individual users. We use tracking information to determine which areas of our sites users like and don't like based on traffic to those areas. We do not track what individual users read, but rather how well each page performs overall. This helps us continue to build a better service for you. 

#### Cookies

We may place a text file called a "cookie" in the browser files of your computer. The cookie itself does not contain Personal Information although it will enable us to relate your use of this site to information that you have specifically and knowingly provided. A cookie can't read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites. Compare and Recycle uses cookies to track user traffic patterns (as described above). 

You can refuse cookies by turning them off in your browser. If you've set your browser to warn you before accepting cookies, you will receive the warning message with each cookie. You do not need to have cookies turned on to use this site. However, you do need cookies to participate actively in message boards, forums and polling. 

#### This website uses Google AdWords

This website uses the Google AdWords remarketing service to advertise on third party websites (including Google) to previous visitors to our site. It could mean that we advertise to previous visitors who haven’t completed a task on our site, for example using the contact form to make an enquiry. This could be in the form of an advertisement on the Google search results page, or a site in the Google Display Network. Third-party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on someone’s past visits to the Compare and Recycle website. Of course, any data collected will be used in accordance with our own privacy policy and Google’s privacy policy.

You can set preferences for how Google advertises to you using the [Google Ad Preferences](https://www.google.com/settings/ads) page.

### Use of information

Compare and Recycle uses any information voluntarily given by our users to enhance their experience of the site, whether to provide interactive or personalised elements on the site or to better prepare future content based on the interests of our users. 

As stated above, we use information that users voluntarily provide in order to send out electronic newsletters and to enable users to participate in polls, message boards, and forums. We send out newsletters to subscribers on a regular schedule (depending on the newsletter), and occasionally send out special editions when we think subscribers might be particularly interested in something we are doing. Compare and Recycle never shares newsletter mailing lists with any third parties, including advertisers, sponsors or partners. 

When we use tracking information to determine which areas of our sites users like and don't like based on traffic to those areas. We do not track what individual users read, but rather how well each page performs overall. This helps us continue to build a better service for you. We track search terms entered in Search function as one of many measures of what interests our users. But we don't track which terms a particular user enters. 

Compare and Recycle may create aggregate reports on user demographics and traffic patterns for advertisers, sponsors and partners. This allows our advertisers to advertise more effectively, and allows our users to receive advertisements that are pertinent to their needs. Because we don't track the usage patterns of individual users, an advertiser or sponsor will never know that a specific user clicked their ad. We will not disclose any information about any individual user except to comply with applicable law or valid legal process or to protect the personal safety of our users or the public. 

### Sharing of information

Compare and Recycle uses the above-described information to tailor our content to suit your needs and help our advertisers better understand our audience's demographics. This is essential to keeping our service free. We will not share information about individual users with any third party without consent, except to comply with applicable law or valid legal process or to protect the personal safety of our users or the public. 

### Security

Compare and Recycle operates secure data networks protected by industry standard firewall and password protection systems. Our security and privacy policies are periodically reviewed and enhanced as necessary and only authorised individuals have access to the information provided by our users. 

### Your consent

By using this site, you consent to the collection and use of this information by Compare and Recycle. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it. 

### Your personal information

When you submit an order via Compare and Recycle you will provide information such as your address, name, phone number and email address. This information is sent to us over a secure connection and will be stored securely.

The information you provide will be passed on to the recycler you have chosen to sell to. This information is necessary in order for your chosen recycler to send you a sales pack (if requested) and to contact you during the course of the sale.

Compare and Recycle will not keep your bank details for any longer than it takes to pass your order onto your chosen recycler. Your contact details will be retained and Compare and Recycle and we will use this information to:

  * Inform you of the latest products, services and offers provided by Compare and Recycle (Atom Juice Ltd).
  * Share with carefully selected third parties (who may send marketing communication to you) unless you opt-out.

We may use any of the following methods to contact you:

  * Email
  * Telephone
  * Text or picture message
  * Post

### Opt-out policy

If you do not wish to be contacted by Compare and Recycle or any of our selected 3rd parties you can opt-out by emaling contact@compareandrecycle.co.uk and requesting that we stop using your information for the purpose of marketing communication. You can also email Compare and Recycle should you have any questions about how we use your information.
